<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on Piotr Kościelniak - passionate programmer</title>
    <link>http://koscielniak.me/tags/conferences/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on Piotr Kościelniak - passionate programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Piotr Kościelniak. Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://koscielniak.me/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>bbq4.it Recap</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/bbq4_it_recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 23:10:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/bbq4_it_recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/bbq4it.png&#34; alt=&#34;bbq4.it&#34; title=&#34;bbq4.it&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On June 24th, 2015, I was returning home from the Devvox PL conference in Cracow. During this journey,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benedykt.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arkadiusz Benedykt&lt;/a&gt;
and I were discussing how nice it would be to organize a conference in our city, Bielsko-Biala.
Then, at the beginning of June 2016
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rekord.com.pl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my company&lt;/a&gt; was thinking about organizing a small meetup for students from our area. It was then that Arek and
I remembered our discussion and we suggested combining our idea with the company’s idea.
After brainstorming, we formulated a plan to organize a small conference in the form of a
BBQ to gather people related to the IT sector in our area. Another brainstorming session lead to the name:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbq4.it/&#34; &gt;bbq4.it&lt;/a&gt; and after some time we had about 75% of the agenda laid out. However,
if it wasn’t for
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/piotr.szymura.37&#34;&gt;Piotr Szymura&lt;/a&gt;, things would have died in the planning stages. He took the weight of preparing the conference, unto his shoulders and thanks to him and the other hardworking people at our company, we managed to organize bbq4.it. Our collective efforts paid off, as we attracted almost 300 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to recall the great time we had through this post. I will share official and behind-the-scenes photos of the inaugural bbq4.it conference which took place on the evening of September 9th, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/preparations.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preparations are in full swing&#34; title=&#34;Preparations are in full swing&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Preparations are in full swing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/precious_gift.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Speaker’s lunch and a mysterious and precious gift for Arek Benedykt given by Maciej Aniserowicz (It’s not a goldfish)&#34; title=&#34;Speaker’s lunch and a mysterious and precious gift for Arek Benedykt given by Maciej Aniserowicz&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Speaker’s lunch and a mysterious and precious gift for Arek Benedykt given by Maciej Aniserowicz (It’s not a goldfish)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/registration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;During registration&#34; title=&#34;During registration&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;During registration (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/welcoming.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Welcoming by Piotr Szymura and Arek Benedykt (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Welcoming by Piotr Szymura and Arek Benedykt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Welcoming by Piotr Szymura and Arek Benedykt (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/opening.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Opening talk by Janusz Szymura - chairman of Rekord Group (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Opening talk by Janusz Szymura - chairman of Rekord Group&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Opening talk by Janusz Szymura - chairman of Rekord Group (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/first_speaker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First speaker - Maciej Aniserowicz immediately after his talk (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;First speaker - Maciej Aniserowicz immediately after his talk&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;First speaker - Maciej Aniserowicz immediately after his talk (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/second_speaker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thanks to Piotr Stapp for giving the second speech during bbq4.it (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Thanks to Piotr Stapp for giving the second speech during bbq4.it&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Piotr Stapp for giving the second speech during bbq4.it (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/break.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;During the break (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;During the break&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;During the break (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/szabelski_drobik.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Krzysiek Szabelski and Marcin Drobik celebrating their victory (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Krzysiek Szabelski and Marcin Drobik celebrating their victory&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Krzysiek Szabelski and Marcin Drobik celebrating their victory (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/jarek_palka.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jarek Pałka debunking another myth (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Jarek Pałka debunking another myth&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jarek Pałka debunking another myth (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/bbq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Barbeque time! (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Barbeque time!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Barbeque time! (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/soccer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IT people and soccer, is it possible? Oh yes. (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;IT people and soccer, is it possible? Oh yes&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;IT people and soccer, is it possible? Oh yes (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/prize.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Handing first prize to the winner. (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&#34; title=&#34;Handing first prize to the winner&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Handing first prize to the winner (Photo Credit: Paweł Mazurczak)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/09/wind_down.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The party was starting to wind down&#34; title=&#34;The party was starting to wind down&#34; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The party was starting to wind down&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are requesting a second edition because they really enjoyed the first. I sincerely hope we can have a repeat next year, and I’ll keep you posted. Anyway, please start praying for good weather for the beginning of September 2017, as it is an outdoor event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Big thanks to my workmate Paweł Mazurczak for allowing me to use his wonderful pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality Excites 2016</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/quality-excites-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/quality-excites-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Quality Excites conference organized by the passionate
&lt;a href=&#34;https://qualityexcites.pl/organizers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt; recently had its 5th edition. For me, this conference was exceptional because there were a lot of workshops and lectures, many of which were dedicated to testing. The speakers practice what they preach and everything related to the conference was high quality, as this is what excites the organizers and the invitees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why &lt;a href=&#34;https://qualityexcites.pl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quality Excites&lt;/a&gt; remains one of my most anticipated yearly events, and every year since 2014, I’ve had the simultaneous fear and thrill of securing tickets. Fortunately, I was invited for the third time in a row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/qe-cake.png&#34; alt=&#34;5th edition Quality Excites - celebration cake&#34; title=&#34;5th edition Quality Excites - celebration cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GGalezowski&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grzegorz Gałęzowski&lt;/a&gt; was also invited as a speaker for the 3rd time in a row and this year his opening speech was titled &lt;em&gt;GIMMEH TDD! - O RLY?&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/qe-grzegorz.png&#34; alt=&#34;Grzegorz Gałęzowski - GIMMEH TDD! - O RLY?&#34; title=&#34;Grzegorz Gałęzowski - GIMMEH TDD! - O RLY?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He talked about his experiences with introducing TDD to teams but what he presented could easily be applied to many other new things which someone may introduce to their team. For me, talks given by Grzegorz are very interesting because they are concise and his presentation style is logical. I’m always impressed by his ability to weave words together, and each thought connects with the previous one and comes from his real life observations, eventually leading to a clear conclusion. You can see Grzegorz’s presentation from the previous Quality Excites conference
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNyMrjMawUY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the opening session, I attended the workshop given by Bartłomiej Michalski and Łukasz Januszek. Workshops are my style and I think the workshops are what make Quality Excites so exceptional among other conferences. They are given for free of charge and are hosted by very passionate people who have great practical knowledge in their field. Additionally, the workshops presenters I spoke with, were all employees of Future Processing. This year, I attended the workshop &lt;em&gt;How to make work more profitable?&lt;/em&gt;. The workshop used an analogy that compared creating processes in a company to creating rules for board games and used this analogy to explain many different roles which people in a team can have and how they influence each other and the situation in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop was insightful and opened my mind to new ideas, it’s given me a lot to think about.
It may be some time before I can use everything I’ve learned in real situations, but I may be able to use one takeaway from this workshop sooner rather than later: being able to discuss unpleasant things with my team as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the workshop and lunch break, I watched three lectures &lt;em&gt;Testing the Internet of things&lt;/em&gt; by Tomasz Janiszewski and Dawid Pacia and then &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: BDD Enterprise&lt;/em&gt; by Tomasz Dubikowski. Both of these lectures were very well-prepared and well-presented but currently I don’t have opportunities to use what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third lecturer which I attended in the afternoon block was given by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/j_palka&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jarosław Pałk&lt;/a&gt;.
I really like this speaker because of his sense of humor, profound knowledge and the way he talks about very serious and sometimes sad things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important part of Jarosław’s speech were sentences like what I’m about to translate. I&amp;rsquo;m paraphrasing from Polish to English, but he said something along the lines of: &lt;em&gt;Developers have benefits, and between these benefits, they create products/services for clients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
By benefits, he meant table football, billiards, ping pong, etc. In his speech, he had a couple of &lt;em&gt;the whole truth about the word&lt;/em&gt; sentences and that’s why I like his talks. I can’t wait to see Jarek at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bbq4.it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bbq4.it&lt;/a&gt; in September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the last talk there was an after-party held in the Future Processing base where we were treated to a cake to celebrate the 5th staging of Quality Excites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/qe-cake-with-organizers.png&#34; alt=&#34;5th edition Quality Excites - celebration cake and organizers&#34; title=&#34;5th edition Quality Excites - celebration cake and organizers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was a well-deserved occasion to celebrate. Quality Excites provides a lot of opportunities to learn new things for free and I would like to thank the organizers for this and I would like to wish all the organisers and participations the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the workshops and lectures held during this conference, they inspired a lot of people including myself. You can see what it means for quality to excite, while attending this conference. It was my third time at Quality Excites and my third time seeing that the organizers believe in quality and provide it in every lecture and workshop. I hope the Quality Excites team keeps going and I hope to see them for the 4th time next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devoxx 2016</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/devoxx-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 23:43:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/devoxx-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The conference beast living inside of me has awoken again but this time it was very hungry and I ended up having to feed it for 4 days. I spent the first 3 days at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://devoxx.pl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Devoxx Poland&lt;/a&gt; conference which ran from June 22nd to 25th.
It is one of the biggest conferences in Poland and this was the second staging. There were 2500 participants and 100 speakers at this edition, and among the speakers, was one of my work mates
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benedykt.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arkadiusz Benedykt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/me-and-team.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me and my work mates at Devoxx Poland, after Arek’s speech&#34; title=&#34;Me and my work mates at Devoxx Poland, after Arek’s speech&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was held at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Centrum_Kongresowe_ICE_Krak%C3%B3w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the International Conferences and Entertainment Center in Cracow&lt;/a&gt;.
I attended a lot of great talks and a couple which weren’t so great, but the most important thing for me was that this event gave me an opportunity to talk with many interesting people and I benefited from this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most fascinating for me was being able to have a quick chat with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mhevery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Misko Hevery&lt;/a&gt;.
Can you guess what his presentation was about? Of course&amp;hellip;it was
&lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angular 2&lt;/a&gt;.
For me, his presentation was one of the best during this conference. He explained how powerful Angular 2 is and why. I met Misko at the speaker’s dinner organized by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metrosoft.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Metrosoft®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started our conversation with the question: “when will Angular 3 come out?”. Misko smiled for a while and something to the effect of “it won&amp;rsquo;t”. I asked him “do you promise?”, and he said “yes I do”. So Dear Community, you can use Angular 2 and don&amp;rsquo;t worry about Angular 3 being released soon. Misko spoke during his speech about many different things related with Angular 2, which you can see in these
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1fRw9VP6LCy4Fl-uruATfLq2V9UY9JBjgQCZaeJlW0WQ/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;.
I asked him how many of them I can use today (23 June 2016) and he said everything. So Dear Community, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to jump into Angular 2 and take as much as you want from it has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/me-and-misko.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Misko and I&#34; title=&#34;Misko and I&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting conversation I had was with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/saturnism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ray Tsang&lt;/a&gt; after the speaker’s dinner.
We talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://kubernetes.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, the cloud, Google, and many others. It was a very nice talk set against the pleasant scenery of the Vistula river and it encouraged me to attend Ray’s presentation the next day titled: &lt;em&gt;Scaling with Kubernetes, Automatically! Learn Kubernetes API through writing a visualizer to an autoscaler&lt;/em&gt;. It was an amazing presentation with very few slides and a lot of real time action with Kubernetes. Honestly speaking, I got lost somewhere in the middle of his presentation but I was happy to attend and it was a pleasure watching how Ray executed one shell command after another and watching him act like a child with a brand new toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up all the presentations: a lot of them were about microservices as many speakers at Devoxx Poland 2016 ended up focusing on this theme. There were presentations on how to: create microservices, monitor them, deploy them, configure a Continuous Delivery environment and other things more or less related to microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like Devoxx Poland because it gives me the opportunity to meet new people and talk with them about the things they couldn’t say on stage. Devoxx primarily focuses on dozens of lectures, but this year that wasn’t the most important part for me. I was focused on meeting new people and communicating with them and this goal was 100% fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/grzegorzduda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grzegorz Duda&lt;/a&gt; and his team for another amazing Devoxx Poland. I hope that he will organise the next edition and I’ll be there next year. I also want to thank Metrosoft® for organizing one of the best parties I’ve ever been to. My goal for next year is to be at this party again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dessert, my conference beast was fed another event and you can read about it in this
&lt;a href=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/06/quality-excites-2016/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wroc# 2016 - knowledge, networking and Objectivity office tour!</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp-2016-knowledge-networking-and-objectivity-office-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp-2016-knowledge-networking-and-objectivity-office-tour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wrocsharp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp/wroc-color.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Wroc#&#34; title=&#34;Wroc#&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days have passed since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wrocsharp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wroc#&lt;/a&gt; conference, however,
now I am finally able to write about Wroc# 2016. For me, this conference lasted three days
and I needed some time to recuperate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Wrocław the day before Wroc# in order to take part in the Pre-wroc# meetup organized
by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/wrocnet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Wrocław .NET User Group&lt;/a&gt;.
It was a nice warm up before the conference. I talked to some old friends and met some new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I went to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stadion_Miejski_(Wroc%C5%82aw)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Wrocław City Stadium&lt;/a&gt;
which was the home of Wroc# 2016. The conference was opened by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lukaszgasior&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Łukasz&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/WojtekZed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wojtek&lt;/a&gt;.
After them, Susanta Ghosh welcomed attendees
on behalf of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objectivity.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Objectivity&lt;/a&gt;.
At the beginning of the conference the organizers informed us of a change in the agenda.
I thought “oh no, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/markrendle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mark Rendle&lt;/a&gt; didn’t come again”,
but It was only partially true. Yes, he didn’t come to the stadium but he was in Wrocław.
So instead of him, the first speech was given by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ICooper&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ian Cooper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian Cooper’s speech &lt;em&gt;From Monolith to Microservices&lt;/em&gt; was a seamless and instructive
talk about: when to go into microservices, how to do it and the benefits for your company,
your customers and you as a developer. Ian as usual, used his profound knowledge and explained
everything in a very consistent way. His speech was a finely woven thread that incorporated
the previous, current and upcoming statement. He composed his speech in a way,
that he showed you both the trees, and the forest: paying attention to fine details
as well as the bigger picture. Ian’s presence was the most memorable part of the conference for me.
I spent awhile talking with him during the after party and this was a very exciting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp/meAndIan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me and Ian Cooper&#34; title=&#34;Me and Ian Cooper&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second speech was given by Mark Rendle, and he spoke about
&lt;em&gt;My First Startup (And Other Mistakes)&lt;/em&gt; and as he said, he was late deliberately
to show us that he makes mistakes. Mark told us about what he learned dealing with
his own businesses. I learnt the following from his speech:
&lt;em&gt;Perfect something. Then add something more, and perfect that too. Repeat&lt;/em&gt;.
That is my summary of his great presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Mark, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ecampidoglio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enrico Campidoglio&lt;/a&gt; came
on stage with the speech:
&lt;em&gt;The Things Git Can Do (that none of the GUIs ever told you about)&lt;/em&gt;.
He tried to tell us that Git is not hard but I am still rather sceptical about this.
I think Enrico didn’t stress enough that using some of the commands
that he showed us can be really harmful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next speaker had a difficult task because she was after the launch break.
And lunch was very tasty and plentiful so certainly everyone was feeling blissful,
which can make you sleepy. Yet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/julielerman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Julie Lerman&lt;/a&gt;,
didn’t let anyone fall asleep. She did a real time demo with a small amount of
live coding and used this to show how Entity Framework Core and
ASP .NET Core 1.0 works on OS X with PostgreSQL database.
I was amazed not only by Julie’s speech but also by
Julie’s attitude and outlook. She is such a happy and positive person,
I am glad that I could meet her in person and that she gave me a lot of positive energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next presenter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ZeroKoll&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris Klug&lt;/a&gt;
was the only one who was among Wroc#’s speakers last year.
Then, he had an excellent performance although he struggled with Visual Studio’s crashes.
Chris is similar to Julie, and has an incredible amount of positive energy
that infected me during his speech. This is so amazing that it actually
doesn’t matter what he talks to you about, you simply
want to listen to him and you have a lot fun.
This time he talked about &lt;em&gt;What Do You Mean “a front-end build pipeline”!?&lt;/em&gt;.
He showed how to use npm, Node.js, Bower, Gulp to process TypeScript and Less.
As an example, he used a very simple angular 1.x application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last presentation before the discussion panel was given by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/condrong&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Glenn Condron&lt;/a&gt;.
This presentation exceeded my expectations.
Glenn show us ASP .NET Core 1.0 and during his presentation
he used the new &lt;code&gt;dotnet&lt;/code&gt; command and almost
the whole presentation was conducted in the live coding style,
which is always a great challenge. I am a big fan of ASP .NET Core and
after this presentation an even bigger fan.
I hope that Glenn and other folks from his team popularise this framework because it is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discussion panel was the last official point in the agenda and
I really liked this point. In Wroc# 2015, it was an impromptu point and
it turned out to be one of the best. This year, it was planned beforehand and
it was even better. This year’s discussion was moderated by Mark Rendle and
he did a great job. Thanks to him the discussion was very dynamic and simultaneously very funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wroc# is famous for its after party. This year it was even better than last time.
There was plenty of delicious food, home brewed beer prepared especially for
this occasion and splash mixes. And foremost, it was an occasion to talk to nice,
wise and friendly people in an unique atmosphere which can only be experienced during Wroc#’s
after parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp/afterParty.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waiting for my dinner&#34; title=&#34;Waiting for my dinner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot state strongly enough how amazing Wroc# is.
This conference is the best one I’ve ever been to. If I had to choose only one conference
every year to attend, it would be Wroc#.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ula-koper-11016817&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ula&lt;/a&gt;,
Łukasz, Wojtek you must put a lot of heart into this conference, and that&amp;rsquo;s why it is so amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post-conference evaluation asked: &lt;em&gt;Would you come next year if we decide to do Wroc# again?&lt;/em&gt;
My answer is definitely YES and I hope that my collection (see picture below) will be bigger next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/wrocsharp/wrocsharpGlasses.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waiting for next beer glass&#34; title=&#34;Waiting for next beer glass&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another question from the post-conference evaluation was:
&lt;em&gt;What improvements would you recommend for our next conferences?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, it’s very difficult for me to imagine a better conference than Wroc#,
so the only thing which I can suggest is a list of possible speakers for the next conference.
I think that what is considered Bleeding Edge now, could be a hot topic next year, and
it would be nice to hear more about it. For example, my list of speakers would include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DamianEdwards&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Damian Edwards&lt;/a&gt; about ASP .NET Core&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/John_Papa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Papa&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bradlygreen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Brad Green&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angular 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nigelpoulton&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nigel Poulton&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;https:/www.docker.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; (this is already a hot topic)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stevensanderson&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Steve Sanderson&lt;/a&gt; about modern Web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebAssembly&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt;
could be Bleeding Edge next year, and maybe it would worthwhile to invite someone to speak about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentors are essential in life and this year I met one of mine at Wroc#: Ian Cooper.
If I could be so bold, I would like to ask the Wroc# team to invite my other life mentor,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/martinfowler&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that my wish list is almost impossible to fulfill but there’s no harm in writing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after the conference, thanks to Ula and other Wroc# team members,
I got a tour of the Objectivity office. It was very nice to see behind the scenes of Wroc#
and to find out first hand what an amazing company Objectivity is.
Thanks to the Wroc# team for this opportunity.
Best to everyone and hope to see you next year at Wroc# 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Boiling Frogs</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/01/about-boiling-frogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 13:33:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/01/about-boiling-frogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve noticed that I am becoming a conference beast. In the last year, I have attended six conferences
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://wrocsharp.com/&#34;&gt;Wroc#&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.dwo.mikstura.it/&#34;&gt;DWO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://devoxx.pl/&#34;&gt;DEVOXX&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://qualityexcites.pl&#34;&gt;Quality Excites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://devday.pl/&#34;&gt;DevDay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://spreadit.pl/&#34;&gt;SpreadIT&lt;/a&gt;)
and five different meetups.
Additionally, this year I may attend even more because new ones have appeared on my conference calendar.
The first conference for me last year was Wroc#. It was an excellent conference.
I can honestly say that this was one of the best conferences I’ve ever been to.
In 2016, I started with another conference - &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/&#34;&gt;Boiling Frogs&lt;/a&gt;, which ended last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference &amp;ldquo;Boiling Frogs&amp;rdquo; was powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://itcorner.org.pl/&#34;&gt;ITCorner - Wroclaw Fellowship of Technology&lt;/a&gt;.
Each presentation at this conference was given by a Polish speaker in Polish.
This event was a good occasion for less known speakers to appear in front of a wider audience, 450 attendees to be exact.
In my opinion, this was a great turn out for their first event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sessions were presented in three parallel tracks, and only the first presentation was made to the whole audience.
It was given by &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/speaker/tomasz-kaczmarzyk/&#34;&gt;Tomasz Kaczmarzyk&lt;/a&gt;, a co-organizer of this conference.
He spoke about the idea behind the conference and about its name.
The name “Boiling Frogs” was taken from the experiment with a boiling frog in a pot.
When we increase the temperature slowly enough, we will be able to boil a frog and it won’t even notice that
it is being boiled. He compared the situation of the frog to a programmer
who is doing their daily tasks without bothering to improve their knowledge and skills and suddenly
they realise that the world has changed. Only then do they realise that they have been boiled, but
it’s too late to jump out. The main idea of these organizers was to alert participants that maybe their pots have
already reached 60 C°, and there is still enough time to jump out of the pot, and change their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the temperature in my pot is not very hot but I may be wrong. Anyway,
I had the great pleasure of taking part in “Boiling Frogs” and I learned some new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the speech given by &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/speaker/bartek-zdanowski/&#34;&gt;Bartek Zdanowski&lt;/a&gt; “Developer, develop yourself”,
I confronted my path of developing myself with the one proposed by Bartek Zdanowski.
And it turned out that they are quite similar, with the exception that I’ve never been keen on hackathons but
Bartek showed that hackathons can be an exciting form of self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the speech given by the co-host of this conference - Tomasz Kaczmarzyk. He talked about pure functional
data structures. I was afraid that it would be a hard presentation that would hurt my brain,
but it turned out that the speaker had a clear path for his speech and delivered it quite smoothly.
Tomasz started his speech with a short theoretical introduction and after this showed us a practical use of
functional structures in GIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Tomasz’s speech, there was a dinner break. I heard that they served 4000 dumplings during this dinner - pretty amazing,
isn’t it? After dinner, I chose to see what &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/speaker/michal-gruca/&#34;&gt;Michał Gruca&lt;/a&gt; had to say. I saw him at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.33degree.org&#34;&gt;33rd Degree conference&lt;/a&gt;,
where he spoke about the mythical 10 times developer. I really enjoyed that presentation, so I expected the same
at &amp;ldquo;Boiling Frogs&amp;rdquo;, and he didn’t disappoint. This was the perfect after-dinner presentation.
I listened to him weave a tale that didn’t include dragons, but another mythical and fantastic creature&amp;hellip;the programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to that lecture, was a presentation given by &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/speaker/pawel-lipinski/&#34;&gt;Paweł Lipiński&lt;/a&gt;.
This one was perfect for the end of the conference. The speaker didn’t bother to prepare slides for his presentation.
He had one for the introduction and then he pulled out his analogue slides (I mean small, yellow index cards)
where he had written bullet points of his presentation and he led us from one point to the other and delivered a very
nice and wise story, in this manner. Examples from Paweł’s speech turned out to be very handy for me at work on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard a lot of talk about a speech given by &lt;a href=&#34;http://boilingfrogs.pl/speaker/michal-plachta/&#34;&gt;Michał Płachta&lt;/a&gt; titled “Paradise for polyglots - panta rei”.
I hope that the organisers make it available to the public, so I can watch it and share it with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the inaugural conference for &amp;ldquo;Boiling Frogs&amp;rdquo;, and I hope it won’t be the last and that the organizers
will manage to repeat this event next year. So, to the conference organisers: best wishes and good luck.
See you next year! And to you my readers: see you next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>