<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asp .Net Core on Piotr Kościelniak - passionate programmer</title>
    <link>http://koscielniak.me/tags/asp-/index.net-core/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asp .Net Core on Piotr Kościelniak - passionate programmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 13:27:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://koscielniak.me/tags/asp-.net-core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrolling in &#34;Daj się poznać&#34;</title>
      <link>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/02/enrolling-in-daj-sie-poznac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 13:27:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/02/enrolling-in-daj-sie-poznac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dajsiepoznac.pl&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/contestLogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Daj się poznać&#34; title=&#34;Daj się poznać&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Maciej Aniserowicz wrote on his blog about starting the second edition of the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maciejaniserowicz.com/daj-sie-poznac/&#34;&gt;“Daj się poznać”&lt;/a&gt;
competition. I’ve decided to take part in this challenge.
I started my blog over three weeks ago and since then I have made two posts.
I think that taking part in this contest will encourage me to have a more systematic approach to my blog.
I think this contest will be a lot of fun and provide a lot of opportunities for me to learn new things.
For the competition I am required to write an average of two articles a week for three months (minimum 10 weeks),
and this seems like a big deal to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest will run from March to May and the winners will be announced in June.
Writing a blog is only one part of this undertaking, the other is completing a project and all blog posts must be
related to this project. I haven’t decided what my project will be but I have the whole of February to brainstorm.
I know that I want to learn and try some new technologies, for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://get.asp.net/&#34;&gt;ASP .NET Core 1&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34;&gt;Angular 2&lt;/a&gt;, and this project will be a good occasion to do this.
Maybe I will also try to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; or another cloud computing platform.
We’ll see, but for sure I want to gain a lot experience from this project.
Additionally, I am going to do this project on Ubuntu 14.04.
ASP .NET Core 1 is a cross-platform framework and I am going to try it out on environments other than Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I’ll be treating this competition as source for many challenges: experiencing new technologies,
regular blogging, and systematic work on my “side project”.
Everything that I am going to use is currently in the Beta stage, so this is another challenge for me.
We will see what happens in June. I hope this will be great fun and that I will have a lot of great experiences,
so&amp;hellip;let’s do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Related posts:&lt;/h3&gt;




&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style: none;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/02/enrolling-in-daj-sie-poznac/&#34;&gt;Enrolling in &#34;Daj się poznać&#34;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/daj-sie-poznac-project-details/&#34;&gt;&#34;Daj się poznać&#34; - Project details&#34;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://koscielniak.me/post/2016/03/i-m-holding-a-project-rider-eap/&#34;&gt;I&#39;m holding a Project Rider EAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>